Guide to the Margaret Brown Dutch Houses Photograph Collection [1920-1936] PR 118
@ 2011 New-York Historical Society
- Series II: Pre-Revolutionary Dutch Houses and Families in Northern New Jersey and Southern New York
  - New York - Rockland County
    - B-58, road to Orangeburg, Blauvelt - Lambert Adriaensen Smidt house (?), [1920-1936] (Box 5, Folder 459-460)
    - B-59, Greenbush Road, Blauvelt - Smidt house (?), [1920-1936] (Box 5, Folder 461-462)
    - B-60 and B-61, Germond Road, Germonds - Major John Smith house and barn, [1920-1936] (Box 5, Folder 463-467)
    - B-62, Cherry Lane, Tallman - Cornelius Smith house, [1920-1936] (Box 5, Folder 468)
    - B-63, Sneden's Landing, Palisades - Sneden house, [1920-1936] (Box 5, Folder 469-472)
    - B-60 and B-61, Germond Road, Germonds - Major John Smith house and barn, [1920-1936] (Box 5, Folder 473-476)
    - B-65, road to Valley Cottage, West Nyack - Tallman house, [1920-1936] (Box 5, Folder 477-478)
    - B-66, Sickletown Road, West Nyack - Terneur-Hutton house, [1920-1936] (Box 5, Folder 479-480)
    - B-67, road to Clarkstown, Germonds - Jacob Vanderbilt house, [1920-1936] (Box 5, Folder 481)
    - B-68, Cherry Lane, Tallman - Zabriskie (?)-Goetschius-Tallman house, [1920-1936] (Box 5, Folder 482)
    - B-69, Pomona Road, New City - Unidentified house, [1920-1936] (Box 5, Folder 483-484)
  - Northern New Jersey - Bergen County
    - No plate, Franklin Turnpike - Hopper house, [1920-1936] (Box 5, Folder 485)
    - No plate, Midland Avenue, Garfield, [1920-1936] (Box 5, Folder 486-488)
    - No plate, Hackensack, [1920-1936] (Box 5, Folder 489-490)
    - No plate, Chestnut River Road, Saddle River, [1920-1936] (Box 5, Folder 491)
    - No plate, B-pg. 299, formerly at Potifly Road, Hackensack - Hopper house, [1920-1936] (Box 5, Folder 492)
    - No plate, Teaneck Road, Teaneck - Kip family house, [1920-1936] (Box 5, Folder 493)
    - No plate, Hackensack - Zabriskie house, [1920-1936] (Box 5, Folder 494)
    - B-70, Chestnut Ridge Road, Saddle River - Achenbach house, [1920-1936] (Box 5, Folder 495)
    - B-71, 184 Essex Street, Hackensack - Abraham Ackerman house, later Brinkerhoff's, [1920-1936] (Box 5, Folder 496)
    - B-72, 651 Polifly Road, Hasbrouck Heights - Johannes Ackerman house, later Brinkerhoff's, [1920-1936] (Box 5, Folder 497-500)
    - B-73, 415 Saddle River Road, Paramus, Ridgewood - Ackerman-Naugle house, [1920-1936] (Box 5, Folder 501-503)
    - B-74, head of Paramus Road, Paramus, Ridgewood - Ackerman-Van Emburgh house, [1920-1936] (Box 5, Folder 504)
    - B-75, East Saddle River Road, Saddle River - Abram Ackerman house; Washington's headquarters, [1920-1936] (Box 5, Folder 505)
    - B-76, 445 River Road, Fair Lawn - Alyea-Outwater house, [1920-1936] (Box 5, Folder 506-507)
    - B-77, Pascack Road, Woodcliff Lake - Hendrick Banta house, [1920-1936] (Box 5, Folder 508-510)
    - B-78, Island Road, north of Ramsey - Brickman (?)-Ackerson house, [1920-1936] (Box 5, Folder 511-513)
    - B-79, 493 Teaneck Road, Teaneck - Hendrick Brinkerhof house, later Demarest's, [1920-1936] (Box 5, Folder 514-520)
    - B-80, Kinderkamack Road, Oradell - Cornelis Cuyper (Cooper) house, [1920-1936] (Box 5, Folder 521-523)
    - B-81, Piermont Road, Closter - William De Clark house, [1920-1936] (Box 5, Folder 524)
    - B-82, French Cemetery, north of New Bridge - David des Marest (Demarest) house, [1920-1936] (Box 5, Folder 525-526)
    - B-84, Schraalenburgh Road, Closter - Abram Demaree (Demarest) house, [1920-1936] (Box 5, Folder 530-532)
    - B-85, Saddle River Road, west of Arcola - Doremus house, [1920-1936] (Box 6, Folder 533)
    - B-86, Schraalenburgh Road, Haworth - John Durie house, [1920-1936] (Box 6, Folder 534-536)
    - B-87, River Road, Fair Lawn - Peter Gerretson house, [1920-1936] (Box 6, Folder 537)
    - B-88, Ramapo Valley Road, Ho-Ho-Kus Township - Garrison house (?), [1920-1936] (Box 6, Folder 538-540)
    - B-89, near the state border, Old Tappan - Cosyn Haring house, later De Wolf's, [1920-1936] (Box 6, Folder 541-542)
    - B-90, Old Tappan Road, Old Tappan - Gerrit Haring house, [1920-1936] (Box 6, Folder 543-545)
    - B-91, Old Tappan Lane, Old Tappan - Frederick Haring house, [1920-1936] (Box 6, Folder 546)
    - B-92, Piermont Road, Rockleigh Borough - Abraham Haring house, later Moses Taylor's, [1920-1936] (Box 6, Folder 547-549)
    - B-93, Pascack Road, Upper Montvale - Holdrum-Wanamaker house, [1920-1936] (Box 6, Folder 550-551)
    - B-94, East Saddle River Road, Upper Saddle River - Hopper-Geotschius house, [1920-1936] (Box 6, Folder 552-554)
    - B-95, 525 Terrace Avenue, Hasbrouck Heights - Isaac Housman house, [1920-1936] (Box 6, Folder 555)
    - B-96, Goffle Road, Midland Park - Cornelis Lozier house, [1920-1936] (Box 6, Folder 556-558)
    - B-98, Hickory Lane, near Piermont Road, Closter - Isaac Nagel (Naugle) house, [1920-1936] (Box 6, Folder 559-561)
    - B-99, Ewing Avenue, Franklin Lakes Borough - Packer house, [1920-1936] (Box 6, Folder 562-570)
    - B-100, 450 River Street, Hackensack - Terheun homestead, [1920-1936] (Box 6, Folder 571-572)
    - B-101, East Saddle Road, Ho-Ho-Kus - Terhune house, [1920-1936] (Box 6, Folder 573-574)
    - B-102, Ramapo Valley Road, Mahwah - Van Alen (?)-Hopper-Van Horn house, [1920-1936] (Box 6, Folder 575-577)
    - B-103, East Saddle River Road, Saddle River - Thomas Van Boskerk (Van Buskirk) house, [1920-1936] (Box 6, Folder 578)
    - B-104, Middletown Road, River Vale - Vanderbilt house, [1920-1936] (Box 6, Folder 579-581)
    - B-105, Wyckoff Avenue, Wyckoff Township - Van Horn house, [1920-1936] (Box 6, Folder 582-583)
    - B-106, Franklin Lakes Road, Franklin Lakes Borough - Van Houten house, [1920-1936] (Box 6, Folder 584-586)
    - B-107, formerly in Jersey City (Hudson County), relocated to Westfield (Union County) - Nicholas Varleth house; Sip homestead at Bergen, [1920-1936] (Box 6, Folder 587)
    - B-108, 125 Lake View Avenue, Leonia Borough, near Englewood - Vreeland house, [1920-1936] (Box 6, Folder 588-590)
    - B-109, 393 Main Street, Hackensack - Westervelt-Bogert house, [1920-1936] (Box 6, Folder 591)
    - B-110, Tenafly Road, Tenafly - Roelof Westervelt house, [1920-1936] (Box 6, Folder 592-593)
    - B-111, County Road, Cresskill - Westervelt house, [1920-1936] (Box 6, Folder 594-597)
    - B-112, Paramus Road, north of Arcola - Zabriskie-Board house, [1920-1936] (Box 6, Folder 598)
    - B-113, New Bridge, North Hackensack John Zabriskie house; Baron Steuben house, [1920-1936] (Box 6, Folder 599)
    - B-114, Paramus Road, south of Paramus, Ridgewood - Zabriskie-Van Dien Smoke house, [1920-1936] (Box 6, Folder 600)
    - B-115, Fairlawn Avenue, Fair Lawn - Unidentified house, [1920-1936] (Box 6, Folder 601-602)
  - Northern New Jersey - Middlesex County
    - B-116, River Road, Raritan Landing, Piscataway Township - Cornelius Low house, [1920-1936] (Box 6, Folder 603-605)
    - B-117, River Road, Piscataway Township - Matthias Smock house, [1920-1936] (Box 6, Folder 606-609)
    - B-118, County Line Road, Franklin Park - Soulard (?)-Suydam house, [1920-1936] (Box 6, Folder 610-611)
    - B-119, River Road, near Bound Brook, Piscataway Township - Jacob Van Deventer house, [1920-1936] (Box 6, Folder 612-613)
    - B-120, Lake Road, Mapleton, near Kingston (Somerset County) - Matthias Van Dyke house, [1920-1936] (Box 6, Folder 614-615)
  - Northern New Jersey - Monmouth County
    - No plate, Middletown - Peter van Couwenhoven house, [1920-1936] (Box 6, Folder 616)
    - B-121, Pleasant Valley, Holmdel Township - Cornelius Couwenhoven house, [1920-1936] (Box 6, Folder 617-620)
    - B-122, north of Hillsdale, near Wickatunk - Jan Covenhoven house, [1920-1936] (Box 6, Folder 621)
    - B-123, Pleasant Valley, Marlboro Township - Conover house, [1920-1936] (Box 6, Folder 622)
    - B-124, Pleasant Valley, Holmdel Township - Hendrick Hendrickson house, [1920-1936] (Box 6, Folder 623-624)
    - B-125, Holland, Middletown - Johannes Luyster house, [1920-1936] (Box 6, Folder 625)
    - B-126, Pleasant Valley, Holmdel Township - Stout (?)-Hendrickson house, [1920-1936] (Box 6, Folder 626-628)
    - B-127, Middletown - Squire John Taylor house, [1920-1936] (Box 6, Folder 629)
  - Northern New Jersey - Somerset County
    - B-128, Rocky Hill - John Berrien house; Washington's headquarters, [1920-1936] (Box 6, Folder 630-632)
    - B-129, Old Rocky Hill Road, Rocky Hill - Berrien (?)-Pumyea house, [1920-1936] (Box 7, Folder 633-634)
    - B-130, road to Blawenburg, Harlingen - Gulick (?)-Ditmars house, [1920-1936] (Box 7, Folder 635-637)
    - B-131, south of North Branch, Bridgewater Township - Gisbert Lane house, [1920-1936] (Box 7, Folder 638-639)
    - B-132, south of North Branch, Bridgewater Township - Lane-Brokaw house, [1920-1936] (Box 7, Folder 640-641)
    - B-133, Somerset Street and Wyckoff Avenue, Raritan - Middagh (?)-Frelinghuysen house, [1920-1936] (Box 7, Folder 642-644)
    - B-134, road to Peapack, Far Hills - Johannes Moelich (Mellick) house, [1920-1936] (Box 7, Folder 645)
    - B-135, near North Branch, Bridgewater Township - Quick house, [1920-1936] (Box 7, Folder 646-647)
    - B-136, Main Street, South Bound Brook - Hendrick and Abraham Staats house; Steuben's headquarters, [1920-1936] (Box 7, Folder 648)
    - B-137, Millstone - John Van Doren house, [1920-1936] (Box 7, Folder 649-650)
    - B-138, Middlebrook, Bridgewater Township - Philip Van Horn house; Sterling's headquarters, [1920-1936] (Box 7, Folder 651-655)
    - B-139, Finderne - Derrick Van Vechten house; Greene's headquarters, [1920-1936] (Box 7, Folder 656)
    - B-140, Easton Turnpike, Franklin Township Symen Van Wickle house, later Suydam's, [1920-1936] (Box 7, Folder 657-658)
    - B-141, Easton Turnpike, Franklin Township - Evert Van Wickle house, later Rev. Abraham Beach's, [1920-1936] (Box 7, Folder 659-660)
    - B-142, Countyline Road, Franklin Park - Jacobus Wyckoff house, later Voorhees', [1920-1936] (Box 7, Folder 661-662)
  - Western New Jersey - Essex and Passaic Counties
    - B-143, Berdan Avenue, Upper Preakness (Passaic) - Albert Berdan house, [1920-1936] (Box 7, Folder 663-664)
    - B-144, Totowa Road, Lower Preakness (Passaic) - Dirck Dey house; Washington's headquarters, [1920-1936] (Box 7, Folder 665-666)
    - B-145, Watchung Avenue, Brookdale (Essex) - Lawrence house, [1920-1936] (Box 7, Folder 667)
    - B-146, Paterson and Hamburgh Turnpike, Upper Preakness (Passaic) - Edo Merselis house, [1920-1936] (Box 7, Folder 668-670)
    - B-147, 367 Goffle Road, Hawthorne (Passaic) - Johannes Ryerson house, [1920-1936] (Box 7, Folder 671)
    - B-148, Paterson and Hamburgh Turnpike, Pompton (Passaic) - Schuyler-Colfax house, [1920-1936] (Box 7, Folder 672-674)
    - B-149, 714 River Road, Passaic (Passaic) - Stynmets-Sip house, [1920-1936] (Box 7, Folder 675)
    - B-150, Fairfield Road, Mountain View (Passaic) - Van Dien house, [1920-1936] (Box 7, Folder 676-677)
    - B-151, Chestnut Street, Nutley (Essex) - Van Giesen-Vreeland house, [1920-1936] (Box 7, Folder 678-679)
    - B-152, Totowa Avenue, Paterson (Passaic) - Gerrebrant Van Houten house, [1920-1936] (Box 7, Folder 680-681)
    - B-153, on the Passaic River, near Fairfield, Caldwell Township (Essex) - Van Ness house, [1920-1936] (Box 7, Folder 682)
    - B-154, River Drive, Passaic (Passaic) - Van Wagening house, [1920-1936] (Box 7, Folder 683)
    - B-155, 868 Goffle Road, Hawthorne (Passaic) - John Van Winkle house, [1920-1936] (Box 7, Folder 684)
    - B-156, 534 East Passaic Avenue, Bloomfield Township (Essex) - Unidentified house, [1920-1936] (Box 7, Folder 685-687)
  - Western New Jersey - Hunterdon County
    - B-157, Stanton - Fitts house, [1920-1936] (Box 7, Folder 688-689)
    - B-158, Stanton - Howsel-Wagoner house, [1920-1936] (Box 7, Folder 690-692)
    - B-159, Van Sickle's, near Clinton - Reynolds-Van Syckel house, [1920-1936] (Box 7, Folder 693-694)
    - B-160, near Three Bridges, Readington Township - Martin Ryerson house, later Quick's, [1920-1936] (Box 7, Folder 695-696)
  - Western New Jersey - Morris County
    - B-161, Two Bridges, Pequannock Township - Thomas Dey house, [1920-1936] (Box 7, Folder 697-698)
    - B-162, near Chapel Hill, Lincoln Park - Dodd house, [1920-1936] (Box 7, Folder 699-700)
    - B-163, road to Boonton, near Towaco, Montville Township - Henry Doremus house, [1920-1936] (Box 7, Folder 701-703)
    - B-164, Changebridge Road, Lower Montville - Farmhouse, at one time Demarest's, [1920-1936] (Box 7, Folder 704-705)
    - B-165, Lower Montville - Johannes Parlaman house, [1920-1936] (Box 7, Folder 706-708)
    - B-166, Changebridge Road, Montville - Van Duyn-Jacobus house, [1920-1936] (Box 7, Folder 709-710)
  - Western New Jersey - Sussex County
    - B-167, Old Mine Road, Sandyston Township - William Ennes house, [1920-1936] (Box 7, Folder 711-712)
    - B-168, road to Port Jervis, north of Sussex, Wantage Township - Stephanus Tietsoort (Titsworth) house, [1920-1936] (Box 7, Folder 713-714)
    - B-169, Old Mine Road, Pahaquarry Township (Warren) - Abraham Van Campen house, [1920-1936] (Box 7, Folder 715-716)
    - B-170, Old Mine Road, Shapanack, Walpack Township - Isaac Van Campen house, [1920-1936] (Box 7, Folder 717-719)
    - B-171, Old Mine Road, Minisink, Sandyston Township - Johannes Westbrook house, [1920-1936] (Box 7, Folder 720-722)
- Series III: Unidentified
  Series III consists of named houses with unidentified locations filed alphabetically; names reflect labeling on the edge of each negative. Where no identifying information is given, houses are arranged by the type of material used in construction. The series ends with an image of a lawn ornament and seven damaged, fragile negatives.
  - Named Houses, Unidentified Locations
    - Faraone house, [1920-1936] (Box 8, Folder 723-725)
    - Maurice Gunn house, [1920-1936] (Box 8, Folder 726-728)
    - MacDonald house, [1920-1936] (Box 8, Folder 729-731)
    - Myers house, [1920-1936] (Box 8, Folder 732)
    - J.D. Van Wagoner house, [1920-1936] (Box 8, Folder 733-735)
  - Unidentified Houses, by Material Type
    - Brick, [1920-1936] (Box 8, Folder 736-746)
    - Clapboard, [1920-1936] (Box 8, Folder 747-757)
    - Stone, [1920-1936] (Box 8, Folder 758-794)
    - Stone and clapboard, [1920-1936] (Box 8, Folder 795-808)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Lawn ornament, [1920-1936] (Box 8, Folder 809)
    - Damaged, fragile negatives, [1920-1936] (Box 9, Folder 810-817)